the hunch we've had is like maybe actually the context that was written
like a year ago when it was like prior Sonnet 3.5.
It's still relevant today so we started to look into it
then we're like, well, what if we delete the whole context from the repo?
Like what would happen?
And what happened for us is actually like the eval started to perform
like much better which was counter intuitive, but it's just like, yeah,
that was pretty big and was listing stuff that was not necessarily useful
so that was really interesting to say.
The AI Native Dev is a podcast for developers and engineering
leads at the cutting edge of AI and agentic coding.
Join your hosts, Guy Podjarny and me, Simon Maple,
every week as we chat with the most exciting voices in
AI and tackle the biggest questions facing developers today.
This is the AI Native Dev.
We just wrapped up two amazing days at AI Native DevCon in London.
But the great thing is that
we get to do it all over again in New York City this November.
You're absolutely right.
We're going to be back in the City that never sleeps on November 3rd and
fourth for more amazing sessions, really engaging hands on workshops and much more.
Yeah, all that great networking, partying, eating and
drinking that you've come to expect from AI Native DevCon.
We think we have one of the best hallway tracks from the business,
and it's the perfect complement to our incredible speakers and presenters.
We'll both be in person and virtual,
with live streamed access to all mainstage keynotes and talks.
Sign up right now for our Super Early Bird ticket for just $100.
Only available for a limited time.
We're really excited to be headed back to the Big Apple, and we hope
to see you all there.
Hello everyone.
Welcome back to the AI Native Dev Podcast.
Today we have a really interesting story about how to build out agent enablement
and learn from it.
Looking at Datadog as an organization that really kind of dove in and invested
in agent and implement
and has a bunch of learnings to tell from the journey
and to guide us through all of that is Simon.
I hope I'm not sort of
too badly.
Simon. Things for coming onto the show.
My pleasure.
So, Simon, we're we're going to do this justice and sort of go
in chronological order on it.
But just to sort of give people a little bit of a teaser of some of the highlights.
I know in the as we as we talked through the journey that I really liked,
we'll talk a little bit about context that actually a fair bit about context,
you know, where did it work for you when you created it?
Where did it create kind of context rot and exaggeration?
And in a way,
I don't know if it's dramatic or standard case,
but a learning about cases where you actually an eval showed you that
if you deleted all the context, it actually actually did better than before.
So that'll be great.
We'll talk a little bit about org and how do you structure and who owns what
the importance of evals.
And and we'll talk about the bottleneck is what are the
what are the problems really that are worth solving.
Because there's infinite work in the world of what are we doing it.
So I'm keen to share all of these stories.
For starters, can you just sort of tell us a little bit about
what is it that that that you do kind of the scope of responsibilities
and maybe a couple of words about Datadog and, you know, like the
large group of engineers that
you're trying to sort of optimize their work for here.
Yeah.
For sure. I'm a director at Datadog.
I manage a part of the org
where called for the language Foundation's.
And so we are serving
about 4000 engineers here at Datadog.
And the way that I described our scope is like,
basically kind of the front end of the day.
It's like everything
people interact with day to day and like how they do their work.
A lot of that falls within my group.
And and a year ago now, we launched like a new
AI dev group to focus on AI
tooling basically here at Datadog.
Yeah, that is sort of a small initiative
there of, you know, maybe, maybe this thing has legs on it.
Cool. Okay.
And I like the definition
of like the front end of the sort of the developer tools on it.
I guess when you have 4000 developers, there's a there's a depth to that as well.
So walk us through a little bit of the storyline
of as you started to, to invest centrally or in general, like
how did the kind of Engineering and Datadog kind of approach
or start opening up the use of agents and a little bit of that timeline
of how we developed it today?
Yeah, yeah.
So for us, it really start at the beginning of, of like 2025.
When, you know, coding as a term was coined.
It was much more talk about it, about this being viable and like
starting to be something that like, really, we could use AI to write code.
And so it's like for us, the big driver, there has been cursor at the beginning.
And so at the beginning of 2025,
we launched like a posse internally with like cursor.
Initially we were aiming to get like 100
maybe 2 to 100 dev to use cursor and just like get some signals of like
how you know, how like it worked for them.
And it just like took off from there.
Like, like we had so many more than 200 people.
We quickly had like a thousand devs using cursor almost day to day
within a month of like launching for this posse.
And so like for us, it was a pretty big signal that I.
Yeah, there's truly something there.
There was a lot of people that I collected find like value in it.
And so yeah.
This is pure pool, right?
You opened the door, you said you can use cursor
and everybody came running in.
Correct.
Everybody wanted to get in and like try it out basically.
And so that's where we started.
And like what like that pull you know towards more AI tool.
We were like well yeah this is going to be transformational to this industry.
And like how we do our work as engineer.
And so and so at that point we decided to okay,
well we will probably need to create kind of a team to, to like own those tools
and like own for the experience around the around I use for the development.
And so at that time, we started to recruit a team that went through
like kind of the whole summer, summer of 20.
Before the recruitment of the team.
The sort of the we over here
is basically you and the people looking at like developer experience and
Yeah.
and frontend are the are the people, I guess before it was designated AI.
Yeah yeah yeah.
Correct, correct.
It was like folks within my, my org rebrand for the city was like
a staff engineer who, like, took the stewardship
of that of the cursor POC.
And I like how you sort of
told me that at some point this was a demand was so kind of off
the list that you had a product manager that found themselves manually.
It was like you weren't ready for the avalanche.
And so someone was like manually adding people's emails into sort of
add them to the cursor list of allowed users.
yeah, yeah.
That was with like, Claude Code over the summer when, like,
Claude came out like it was the second wave of adoption and like that tool.
So at first we, we had issues to set up for SSO.
So I'm not exactly sure why, but that didn't work.
And so we needed to add manual email to like to like Claude Code
basically to get access to people.
And yeah, a PM took that role of like basically managing access to that tool
over the summer until we could figure out the SSO bug we were running into.
Some of that running in the the sort of the era of AI.
So sorry, I kind of disrupted your flow, though a little bit.
I sort of I love that story too much.
So you had cursor, you decided to hire someone
and then you went on to to start Claude Code, I guess.
How did Claude Code enter the scene here?
Yeah.
So so because the product we're already working with
the Anthropic models, we had connection already in like in a contract.
And so just like someday clockwork came out and people could basically use it
because we had API keys and so
and so yeah, it just was available overnight.
And I think, you know, people pay kind of attention
to like the news cycle what like people are like or like saying.
And there was a lot of hype around Claude Code at that time.
And so it basically organically grew
from that point.
Would you say like the
Claude Code adoption history at this point versus present?
But would you say Claude Code adoption was was as
as fast as as the cursor one because cursor.
They really nailed the kind of low friction you're already in.
It'll give you superpowers, you know?
So why wouldn't you want cursor?
While Claude Code was more like more of a big change to it
that clearly super compelling, but still the appeal was the same.
Or was cursor adopted faster?
That is hard to say.
I'm not sure.
You know, it's like both at that point, you know, towards the end of
the summer of 2025 because I think the story changed later. But
at that point they pretty were like pretty similar.
And I think they were catering to like different personas.
Let's take like people especially for us, where
maybe piece of context, like we have huge mono repos
and so we know like vs code on those tends to perform pretty badly.
And so the base of cursor
and some of our mono repos was causing issue for adoption of
just like being not performant enough for the large repos we're having.
And so there was like some of those people
had a much better kind of experience with, with code running in a terminal.
Like you don't need to have the IDE running.
And so for a lot of people, that was more compelling,
I think just from like a performance reason.
And so I think like that drove a lot of people there.
And then all of our power user quickly flipped over to Claude Code,
because I think what they were seeing is like, they don't need the IDE
open, you know, they could do most of their work without an IDE open.
And so for them, that adoption for the power user
was like pretty clear early on.
Got it.
Yeah. And so this is so we're about a year ago.
We're sort of like approaching summer of 25 at this point.
Okay. So talk us through. So cool. So we've had that.
You had a cursor just sort of lumped in.
You decided to hire while you're hiring.
You sort of have this sort of Claude Code, you know, land in your lap
and you're managing sort of added, you know,
that sort of a so and then you started to build a team.
Yeah, yeah yeah.
We started to build a team.
So so like one of our early champion was in the M here at Datadog.
We offered them to do kind of a team switch and build this new team.
We started to recruit people for that team.
We had a few transfer come in as well.
Yeah.
And so yeah, we started to put that team together.
We wanted to do
everything, but you got to decide where you start.
And so for that team initially we started really
like focused on like metrics and just getting more metrics into like
what is going on, what is the impact, what is the cost as well.
And on the other side, we knew already that like I was pretty expensive.
And so and so we wanted to start to be able to like benchmark different models.
What is the best solution?
And so we created a team or like that team started to work on evals
and like building kind of an agent and coding
tool eval platform
to help us make decisions about like
which model, which tool we should onboard at Datadog.
This is.
So this is like an early embrace of evals, which I appreciate, you know,
sort of big fans here at Cecil.
And how did you how did you apply that.
So like what are examples of things that you develop.
We'll dive in more.
So I'm still in like journey mode, but these sort of earlier days
it was sometimes hard like you might draw conclusions from an eval, but it wasn't.
It's not always easy to think about how would you apply that learning.
So what are examples of like should we do X
that you've decided?
Yeah.
So the first application of evals for us
very concretely was for code review.
And we had a bit of back and forth and like,
you know, what's the value of AI in code review?
And I think if you've worked with a tool that is very nitpicky,
you know, it's not really fun to work with and nitpicker that is not a human.
And so and so we stopped pretty early on the like
really for us, the distinction here would be like
we wanted to put AI in the loop for code review to really, like prevent
an incident or like kind of major bug and like really like focus on that,
you know, as like kind of a last guardrail before you go to production.
And so the first evals we did
was like replaying PRs we knew had caused incident.
And then like catching, you know,
are they going to figure out that this is going to fail actually.
And so, you know, we do track a lot of data around
incidents here at Datadog in a data set.
And so we had all that data already kind of there for the picking.
And so we were able from there to like devise and basically build
a platform that would replay PRs and then run the whole agent review.
And then with an agent judge being like, well, does that, does that
review command point out what is going to cause an incident later on?
Yeah.
Super smart because it's like a clear use case
because oftentimes the difficulty is defining what correct is.
But if you have those historical incidents.
So I want to dig into evals.
But let's just sort of complete maybe the timeline.
So you went ahead.
You sort of hired hard or like moved this internal person
and you started building a team.
And I know maybe fast forwarding to today,
as that team evolved, you now have two teams, right.
Like now that you're sort of a bit more mature,
maybe tell us
a little bit about current setup and then we'll we'll move on to evals.
What it says?
Like we had a lot of ambition around, like changing the way we work with AI.
But towards the beginning of the year, what we saw
is like that first team that we built,
they had a ton on their plate with evals,
with metrics, with like cost management and all of that.
And so it was really hard to then like, you know, carve out
a piece of time for us to actually work on, like rethinking how we work.
And at the same time, at the beginning of the year, I think everybody saw with Opus
4.5 that came out just before the holidays, the
like adoption from their reader, like, took off like really, really fast.
You know, pretty
everybody says like the amount of like PR pretty much doubled overnight,
you know, and it started to really show kind of
bottlenecks in our flow in the CI
that are way more serious than they were before.
And then it was hard to carve out time to actually like focus on that.
Namely for us right now is like really code reviews,
like pretty like the big bottleneck that we're trying to tackle.
And at that point we're like,
well, we need more people to to work and like really focus
on the experience itself of like, you know, the slack with AI
and not just more kind of the governance and like, signals side of the world.
And so we like launch like a second team.
I forgot exactly when, but towards the beginning of the year.
Yeah. No.
Very cool I love that I like the names you sort of mentioned to them.
So just signal and flows like very does what it says on
the tin type names
and just I guess for it's useful sometimes
as people calibrate for them to sort of think about rough sizes of those teams.
Like it's kind of you have circa 4000 engineers in total was sort of the rough
sizes of these two teams.
Yeah.
So we're aiming to have six people, around six people in a kind of both team
and was recruiting for that second team.
Got it.
Yeah.
It's not a good ratio, you know, in terms of of multiplications and leverage.
Yeah, yeah.
So about 12 people for 4000 engineers.
Yeah.
And the
I guess as the organization flows this maybe
like one last question on the team thing before we continue as you change
the the way that you work and the adaptation did
did a need for new signals come out like because I think the previous team, like
the signal team is very much around current way of working.
Let's sort of measure output.
So we see if productivity improves or costs change, etc.
but now that you change it, did you find the same metrics work over time or do you
did you need to kind of invent new metrics or sort of start measuring do things?
So I don't think we've had to change dramatically
how we measure, you know, productivity.
But I'd say like we're using a lot like Dora metrics.
And these tends to be more
you know, they're not like leading metrics.
There are lagging metric.
And so and so looking more into like the leading metrics
and like what's in there I think usually we need a bit more creativity.
And and those are usually kind of less
like two signals or like your piece of the pie.
And it's hard to isolate exactly what moved those metrics.
So, so like what I'd say maybe
like what has been more visible is more like how we think of cost
and like the amount of, like token we're using.
And then so like, you know, just like
being more professional and like handling costs of AI, like, like, you know,
with now everybody at the company basically using AI, using more of it,
there's a bit, you know, it does increase for the budget that goes towards AI.
And so like
we just need to be more cognizant of this
and just make sure that is disused reasonable and so
and so definitively more on the cost aspect of it that we've done.
And then the other thing is like with evals, and now that we
that we're getting a bit more data, then like the question comes up like, well,
how do you turn that into action or like to know what to do with the evals?
And so it's like pretty like those two aspects have changed more
in terms of productivity metrics themselves.
Were still mainly looking at like durable metrics overall to get to get signals.
Yeah.
Yeah. Interesting. Yeah. Makes sense.
And I guess
did you ever get into token mixing or is that because you mentioned cost?
Like you're sort of aware of how much it cost before?
That sounds a little bit counter like I want this successful but I want it
responsibly successful.
No, no, not like token maxing.
We never did quotas for example.
And so and so we're trying to like really not go there because,
you know, if you need a lot of token because of what you're working
on, you know, we kind of do want people to have the opportunity
and be intentional about for their for their own use and their own needs.
And so, you know, it's like maybe a bit like breeding hot
and cold at the same time, but we're really more looking into like
systematic way that we can reduce token or like compress output,
you know, things like that.
Cool.
Okay. Thanks for sort of the rundown there.
Sort of on the team who've done it.
We started sort of teasing out a little bit
this sort of investment in in evals, you know, and creating it.
And I think
I thought that was really interesting because this is very much
like a world of vibes, right.
I'd say even until today, you know,
like if you're building an AI product, everybody will say,
but if you are talking about sort of development with the with agents,
or if you're talking about even sort of like a generic workflows as a whole.
I guess kind of showing my bias a little bit.
It's like,
I feel like there's a lack over there, like the vibes are quite dominant on it.
And so I like that you that you kind of create those.
Can you tell us a little bit about what what works like you've invested in evals.
We don't really need to go through the whole journey of like where you are today.
What is it that you do today with evals?
Maybe tell us a little bit about the tech stack, but also what's
what is the value that you sort of derive out of them.
And maybe where are they.
Not in yet.
Okay.
So, so like for us it's a fully custom.
Solution written in go with like sandboxing.
So I don't know, you know,
when we started, if there was a lot of open source option,
we pretty like looked at a few, you know, but nothing was like really mature.
And so like we just went our own way since like it was not like overly complex
for a pure use case of like AI agent.
And then Datadog has a pretty good metric.
Platforms like it was easy
to just feed the metrics in there and then consume it from Datadog directly.
So in terms of like what
we do today with the evals, just like maybe
like two things that we're looking at really specifically
on one side, it's like just like tracking performance
of like new models, especially for the open weight model
and trying to get a sense of like, when could that be a viable alternative?
Or in which fashion could they be?
And on the other side is like, how does the what, you know,
things like steering documents
are they are they working when we change it?
Does it change the performance of the evals?
And so like really more on a on the performance side
where like teams that are not us are going to own streaming documents,
maybe should own the streaming documents because we can talk of ownership.
There sometimes is a bit hard within repositories and just
like tracking a bit the performance like is there any shoe and like
should we change it in, in which form should we change them?
And did you maybe there's like two different sort of conversations here.
Sorry. I started both together there.
Maybe one is like let's talk
a little bit about the stack and then we go to the substance.
So on the stack you build your own because you have your sort of Datadog
platform, kind of very good at collecting data and aggregating it.
And I guess at the time nothing else was mature.
Do you think people should build the system, or would you say,
like, if you were to do this again today, you'd probably pick a harness
or sort of one of the existing frameworks for it?
Or do you think there's sort of aspects of how you do the eval
that, that you feel like they need to be custom, they need to be yours?
Yes. I don't feel.
Like strongly about custom versus hosting platform.
I think what's important is like to be able to support multiple
harnesses, multiple models from different source.
I think it's pretty important, but as long as you have that and I think
like most of the platform, do offer it, I think going with like with,
like an off the shelf solution is pretty, pretty good.
But I'd say also coding being less of an issue today
for us, it's been fairly easy to put it together.
It wasn't that hard.
To build the system.
So I guess so, so I think I think that that sort of makes sense.
Like technically, just to be able to run an agent and sort of have a card
or like some sort of scorecard and run that and aggregate the data,
you know, those are kind of within core competencies.
And I guess you kind of always way that a little bit against okay.
But why reinvent it.
You know like if you if it's not that custom.
So it's a decision I guess all developers are sort of fairly familiar with.
The second question that I have is maybe a bit more in
the substance is at the beginning, you talked about
use cases that made a lot of sense, that are central
and have clarity about what the truth is.
So I guess my question
is, as you approach use cases that are sort of more elaborate,
and you talk about using models and all that,
like what is correct is not always as clear cut.
So I guess how do you how do you handle that?
And maybe like who even write that down, you know, today.
Right. Like who creates the eval scenarios.
So in terms of evals
and like writing those evals,
there's a few different things that we're doing
and like new stuff that we're trying out.
Now. The status quo so far has been we've wrote the first ones with
like very common use case to just like have a baseline that we can go through.
And then we went out to pretty much like all of the platform teams and like
ask them to to add evals, you know, to cover their, their own platform use.
And so really spread out for the ownership
of those evals across a company and just like get more support.
The downside of that though is that,
yeah, it is limited in a way of like if as a dev you're using
like like a harness or like an engine tool,
like you're pretty, not only asking them to do very specific things,
there's a lot of the work that's more on the creative side, finding ideas.
What should you do?
What's the right approach to your problem?
And this we don't try to cover with the evals
we have because it's just like so broad.
It's just like really hard to know what exactly should you try.
And you know,
if it's always the same question, then like you only have this like a small slice
but like kind of the creativity aspect, I think it's somewhere or like something
that's like really hard to gauge with an agent.
And so I don't have a great answer to that,
but I know it's a whole that we're having and we're like,
fine to live with this gap that we're not sure how to fill yet.
Maybe someday I can come back and like, maybe we figure it out.
But for now, we're not too much trying to tackle that.
So you just sort of echo back over here.
You're saying at the moment
where you're sort of seeing the value in a bit of a concrete fashion
is in finding cases that have clarity about truth, that repeatable processes.
You're doing the thing again and again,
and generally the scenarios and all that are written fairly centrally,
not just by you, but by you mentioned platform teams.
So like it's not really not going to the end developers.
They're not really writing evals.
These are extractions out of real world scenarios of evals
that change at a slightly lower pace, broadly speaking.
And you think eventually like if you're if you were kind of a betting man, right.
And you sort of say in a year's time, do you think
all developers write evals or do you think it stays this way?
This is like a crystal.
Ball question. So no, you do it. But.
Yeah, no, but I have a good answer for you here.
I don't think every dev is going to be writing evals.
So what we're doing right now.
So you know, TBD if it's going to work.
But I'm pretty confident
that it's going to be the right solution for us going forward.
We are tracking
for the trajectories of agents and what they're doing.
And so we're tracking a lot of data today for the use of agent within Datadog.
And so what we want to do is like go from that to raw data of like,
well this from came in, the agent did that, etc.
and like extract from their common scenarios that tend to recur or
like common type of interaction that a user have with a given platform,
and then using an agent to turn that into actual evals.
And so basically taking like real data,
like how people use the agents and make sure that we're covering,
you know, a fair amount of overlap with actual use.
And we pretty confident that we can automate most of that.
Yeah.
No, I love that.
That is actually very aligned with sort of our experience at
all, which is the more you anchor it in concrete cases, the more real it is.
And then, you know, like what the developer is not like doing.
They don't like writing docs, they don't like writing tests.
And so now you're sort of saying, hey, write dogs and tests.
You know, that doesn't really work.
And and so probably the best ease of use
aspect to it is instead of asking devs to write those tests
or write those events and errors, you you observe them,
you sort of extract them out of the loop and you extract these scenarios.
I guess there's still it's an unavoidable future sort of evolution to that
that you will still need.
Like these things are dynamic and so you still captured that scenario,
that sort of hypothetical aggregate PR at least that's the case
in our world, right?
We've observed a bunch of prove created a scenario.
You're running it.
You're still capturing that in some files.
That's it in some repo.
And over time it will rot, right.
Like over time it will no longer represent your system.
And so there has to be some maintenance.
So at some point someone needs to own that right.
And that someone is hopefully someone who can kind of
represent developing in this repo.
Right. Or something. Like that.
Yeah, I agree,
but I think it just, you know, it's hard to catch wrath and it's hard
to come back to, to like case you created in the past because
like the amount usually that you end up with is like fairly large.
And so we're really focused on a on auto mission here.
So like really having an agent's to, to do for the sweeping
and the really is bring up the signal but eventually maybe even make the decision
about like which case are still relevant today.
Yeah, I think I buy into that.
I think in general, whenever you introduce a human, you, you create a bottleneck.
We'll talk about that in a sack.
But whenever you introduce a human and so, so you have to plan ahead for this.
And in that sense, the sort of the users, both the authors and the users of
the evals are very likely to be to be agents.
So you still need to create them, but it's not necessarily the person that creates.
It might be the, the someone else.
And I guess the before we kind of move on a little bit
from evals on it, how how often do you run the eval.
So like once you, once you agree that something is correct,
is this, is this something you, you deem after the fact?
You run them on every context change?
Do you run them? Yes.
How how do the how does the execution
of the evals integrate into this SDLC?
Yeah.
So today we're doing nightly evals.
So we're running basically once a day.
And then for PR that might specifically target evals
like they're changing streaming documents in like a heavyweight really trying to
to like change for the results for those people can do like an ad hoc run.
And you're probably gonna want to do a few since like evals or not
always super stable to get to give a statistical significant results.
Got it.
Very cool. So this is you run nightly.
You look at relevant changes, some steering dogs that have sort of modified.
If those occurred you run the eval.
If there's a an apparent regression, you, you, you point
that out to the to the person so you don't get in the way and you run them.
I guess
it's sort of consistent with the previous theme,
which is you run them on the things that you, you feel like you truly know,
as opposed to trying to speculatively anticipate ahead.
Correct.
Okay.
And that probably results in something that like costs wise,
is not that big a deal.
How expensive are these events getting?
It's a good question.
I'm not sure, but evals are expensive.
They're cheap enough that that they haven't doubled. You're
yeah, yeah, I don't know compared to the coding agents use.
Yeah. Yeah it is. It is nothing compared to.
But it's definitely something that we're cognizant of.
And like the decision to run it might be is obviously part of that.
We're like, well if we were on prepare obviously it's a
that is going to be too expensive.
It's interesting. You know we've we've been experimenting.
This is of course
sort of in intensive itself but also kind of with customers.
And the one of the observations is that you can actually use
cheap models like open, cheap open models to assess regressions.
So we found that deep seek actually correlates
pretty well in terms of the skill uplift for a variety of tasks.
And so what you can do is it doesn't need to be as good at overall the tasks.
But if you measure it with the skill.
Now that one is like a lot.
It's fast and it's cheap.
And so maybe you can run that sort of deep before flash
as part of your CI test for some sort of selection.
And so you find it because it has all the sort of the natural problem.
If someone made a change yesterday and you're coming back to them tomorrow,
it's annoying.
It's rework.
It's better if it's in line. Have to weigh that.
So I don't.
Know precisely where it lands, but I feel like there is an evolution of evals
expanding as tests, right?
Just like we have some tests that we run in the CI,
and some tests that are too expensive or slow to run in the CI.
I think we'll have the same for emails.
I think that is exactly correct.
And it's also the way we're thinking about it. Right.
Like what you can run after the fact.
I'm like, you know, what's what's like the cost of a revert,
like a rollback versus the cost of like that.
Like you pay now waiting before you can merge something.
And so it's not always a pure trade off,
but we need to try to be kind of cognizant of the cost
of making a mistake versus
the cost of waiting for things to run or paying for the inference or run into.
Very cool.
Okay, cool.
So I love the passionate vowels and I can kind of geek out about evals.
I've built a passion for them.
But let's talk a little bit about context.
So in the process of that
you referred here to sort of steering context and all that.
What is the sort of the state of context typically
within Datadog or people like?
Is there a central context that people share?
It is mostly in repo, like how would you describe like skill adoption right now?
Give us a bit of a picture of where is context being used.
Focus on dev within within the organization.
Yeah.
So it's like there's like two, two big source.
One is files that are just committed to to the repository themselves.
I'd select skills is now mainly what there is.
There's not a lot of other stuff that is not skills.
Skills as you know has been pretty well adopted.
Yeah.
And then we have the cloud marketplace with a lot of skills there as well
that is centralized.
And I can talk of like mistakes and like all of those as well
Yeah, that's what I'm talking.
I think you had a movable sort of insight.
So what did it work?
Let's start. Let's start positive.
Where did words that have seen working?
Yeah yeah.
So I mean what what's worked really well is like
everybody contributed early on and especially when we started, you know,
without the central team was like if you see just like get people onboarded,
you know, I think it was good to not put too much structure early on
so we can try and see what work and like, have learnings out of it.
And so I think for the for the barrier
and the friction early on was like really low.
And I think that was
probably the right move to do because we want people to be contributing
and we want the best idea to win and those ideas to be easy to share.
I love that the kind of core principle about transformation at the beginning,
you're trying to drive adoption on efficiency.
Just just sort of get people in the boat.
But then what we saw two time is the more user we've
had, the harder it became to go and like change them
because the impact you're having then, you know, instead of like being on like
200 people doing kind of a posse with you, like using the same tool,
you're going to impact like 4000 people working on the repository.
And so like it's just like much more stressful
to like break things for like so many people.
And then also the size became kind of hard to manage.
Like the cloud marketplace has hundreds of plugins.
So, you know, if you're once you install the marketplace, like
do you know which plugins are good,
which one should you use, which one are going to perform better?
And so what we've steered people to do is more team based marketplace
for them to share, for their own flows within the team, things that are specific
to their team or marketplaces, extension for specific platforms.
So if you work with platform X or we'll
we will suggest in the documentation that you install that marketplace
and those plugins for you, or will refer to it from context document
where the agent can suggest to install the marketplace
and stuff like that.
Very interesting.
So like groups of context so people know where they're approaching
that and they control that because kind of slightly hinders
maybe like reusability, you might sort of have different teams.
You probably do have different teams that do that, but you slightly control
the chaos in this fashion.
Yeah yeah yeah yeah.
Correct, correct.
And then what I'd say we found out at the beginning of the year,
Pi became like pretty popular recently.
And so, so we saw many people like starting to hint at like the fact
that like Pi somehow was just performing better than the alternative we had.
And like the.
To clarify, for those who don't know that Pi is the very
highly customizable, custom, hackable harness, but it's open source.
But then you can customize on top of which Open Claw is built.
Exactly.
And so one thing is like by default, it's not going to be the lot of the context.
And so and so kind of the hunch we've had is like maybe
actually the context that was written like a year ago
when it was like prior Sonnet 3.5.
It's still relevant today in the world of Opus
4.8 or GPT-5.5.
Right. Like maybe not.
And so we started to look into it and then we're like, well,
what if we delete the whole context from the repo?
Like what would happen?
And what happened for us is actually like the eval started to perform
like much better once we deleted the whole context,
which was counter intuitive, but it's just like, yeah, that was pretty
big and was listing stuff that was not like necessarily useful or,
you know, that should not go into like a steering document.
And so that was really interesting to say.
I love that sort of insight.
It's it's kind of a real world manifestation of how context rots
and sort of so familiar that software rots, that it goes from kind of
being useful to being useless, to being harmful on it.
And for context, like we don't have that muscle memory yet on it.
So now you're seeing it with the skills and guess what was the result of.
So the insight is great.
It sounds like you still ran
those evals centrally because it was like you or your teams kind of thinking,
you'll do that. You ran the eval you found out.
It's actually outperforming having context,
I guess. What could you do about it?
Could you sort of go off and say, cool, let's delete the context.
How did you handle.
yeah, yeah.
So I think if we didn't have data to back it, it would be pretty controversial.
And just like to to be clear, this was owned by the front
end team that run for the front end mono repo.
They're both evals.
They did the for the for the testing there.
And like they wrote new guides of like what should you do instead of context.
And so like that was fully something that was owned but by the sort of team
within my original but but but like not like by the AI
team and so
and so yeah.
With the data
backing this decision, a lot of people were surprised by this decision.
But the data was like really clear that it was performing much better.
And so and so people agreed with it like very easily once they saw
the for the data. Yeah.
So I think like two to sort of interesting tidbits over here is
like one is you removed the context, but it's because you have started
forming a harness.
So right.
You're saying this was not just because the models got better,
but also because you started working with more custom
harnesses.
Oh this is something we're
doing now but it's not what led to that decision.
Yeah.
So this
I guess is still primarily either the model improvements or just
those context files were created at one point in time
and they no longer represent reality for the agent.
So anywhere between the new models don't need them.
And they're just wrong at this point.
Correct.
I don't think they were wrong per se, but I think it's early on.
There was a lot of like basics like you would try to retrain the agent on.
Yeah.
So in the case of the front end repo, there was a
like a whole paragraph in like how to use yarn.
And I'm pretty sure now it's part of the training set of,
of like the models out there.
And so, you know, we don't need to retrain it.
Yeah, yeah, that makes sense.
And context is a scarce resource.
And so over time, like if you accumulate enough of that, you, you,
you take away from, you get a I love this all one talking with someone talked about
how the the model gets into dumb mode, you know because of the.
Yeah yeah.
Yeah. Exactly.
And so in terms of the governance around context,
if you want to do a bit in there is what we saw is like actually like
I think we have an inclined to just go in and add something to like an agent.
But very often it just has easy as
like is the error message from that tool clear.
And do you provide next step of like what should you do instead.
And so we've been also moving
or like pushing people that like, you know, when they run into like
kind of an issue where the agent doesn't do what you want it to do.
Well, where, where,
where like can we provide that context when it's necessary instead of like
trying to train the agent ahead of time into how to do everything,
especially within a modern repo where like, there's so much going on,
you just cannot provide all of the context upfront.
And that seems to be detrimental.
Very good.
So I think a whole bunch of lessons from here.
One is the importance of evals.
So you can make data driven decisions to is maybe a reminder around
how context does rot over time.
So you have to have some sort of plan around
how would you sort of reassess it, which comes back to evals.
But even if you're just vibing it like still do something
like be proactive around updating it and then,
you know, maybe just a little bit more as you write new context,
solve problems, don't anticipate them as you as you go.
Which I guess comes back to the observability and the loops. Right?
Because today, probably the best practices don't actually solve problems,
like just sort of solve a problem in the spot
and create the loop to, to identify, manage that context.
And you like when we spoke, you talked about how you think
one of the theories of how the context got accumulated in the repo
was because of this sort of loss aversion, like when someone wrote it, it was hard.
And maybe this comes back to evals
is, you know, it just sort of feels fearful to delete it,
like maybe it is useful somewhere on it is that do you want to about that?
Yeah.
Yeah, absolutely.
I think like as people propose to remove stuff from,
from like that root AGENTS.md file like
like even in like PR review comments.
People are like, well,
are you sure that like you should be doing this because like,
maybe it provides value to somebody somewhere.
And so I think, yes, it's
when you remove something and you don't replace it with something new.
It is just hard to do,
especially when you're having an impact on like hundreds
or thousands of engineer at once is like it's hard to have certainty.
And so if you don't have data to back those decision, it is really hard to
to like take the step to go ahead and do it
or like feel the permission or feel that you're
that you have a good reason to do it.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
I'm 100% in agreement and it's I love to see it in manifest.
So I guess like in those marketplaces that you have in the small ones
coming back a little bit to what do you create evals for?
I mean, this sort of logic will imply that whether now or soon, like,
are you starting to feel that
within each of these teams marketplaces, they need to have evals
for how how well these skills like for the things that are shared,
like it goes to reason to say like they also need the valves
because otherwise they'll have the same problem.
Yeah, yeah for sure they will.
I think like maybe one of the challenges is also just like the distribution
of those skills.
Does everybody have them install when they need them.
And so there's a bit of a challenge there of like making sure,
do people have the right tool for the task that like they want to do.
And I'm not sure the way we're working today
with like local agent only and like everybody set up
for their own thing, there might be limits to that eventually.
And so I'm not exactly sure what is going to be the right solution going forward.
But I think meta harnesses, for example, are pretty interesting to that of like,
you know what if we
we have kind of a classifier and we know well, this is touching platform A.
So let's run this with an agent that has those skills pre-installed.
And like if this was centralized for example,
like I think that might be able to provide a much better kind of experience.
Like we have a better baseline that don't rely on like
tribal knowledge or like somebody having read documentation.
Yeah, I agree, I feel I think generally people
underestimate the importance of environment definitions in evaluations.
And so I think that's at least how we translates in our world.
We created this project evals versus sort of scale evals.
They're actually all just the same events just of names.
And the idea was the scale values I think you test in isolation.
And so it's a good way to sort of test if it regresses or not.
So that that needs to tackle.
That first problem, which you correctly pointed out
is a bit hard, which is defined what correct is because it runs together.
And then and then you get into the problem of like,
okay, that's nice and well,
but I actually have 30 skills installed when I'm running this, not one.
And so does it work in that environment.
And that basically gets infinite. Right.
Which which skills do you have at what time and how do you.
And so I think environment management like the thing that we've
sort of seen extend in flexibility, but then it's also in complexity.
You have to think about how to rein that in.
It's just that all these definitions of
how do you define the environment within something runs.
And I guess they both boil down to trying to eliminate works on my machine
scenario. Right?
Like the one is define what correct is and define
the machine of like a like defined works and define machine.
And you can step out of of that.
So it's interesting and it sounds like that's still sort of a work in progress.
Like at the moment in practice, these little marketplaces
I don't know if little, but like t marketplaces don't tend to have events.
Yeah.
So these are a fascinating conversation that we started running out of time here.
So maybe sort of chat a little bit about about kind of open models on it.
Maybe I'll sort of open models and bottlenecks.
So you started by sort of talking about how the
the evals were useful to assess models.
And, you know, you've alluded nerds
of previous conversations, how today the bottleneck is very much
in the review phase of it and where we work over there.
So I guess maybe I'll kind of ask you
a little bit of a joint question of it, which is, you know, where are you
and what are your views around the review bottleneck, what to solve it?
And have you tried open, open models on those?
Yeah.
So based on our evals,
I think open weight model to be like fully viable,
assuming the bar does not move as progress happen in the space would be
that they would need to perform about 50% better than they are today.
But caveats.
Is a statement even for like GLM 5.2 and like the latest
or is it like a notch below.
No, a notch below.
We didn't yet run the evals on those.
But we're very excited about this because
yeah yeah yeah.
And the caveat being like also for the
for the creativity of those models with like tasks that are unknown or
larger task instead of the execution part of it.
And so this we don't have signals
from our evals, but we're looking at public evals on
to get some signal there and then getting user feedback.
So at the moment when you run
like say code reviews or these like highly repeatable processes, today
you're still with the frontier models writing those.
Yeah.
For code review today we are we're having the background agents that
for example for code review the first one rerelease is like if your CI fail
and it's like a linting error or formatting error, stuff like that.
And like that's pretty easy to offset to like an agent to just go fix it for you
so you don't need to like, come back and like have to deal with it yourself.
And so we're trying to remove friction from, from different places.
And, and like a lot of those tasks can be done because well by like
like an open weight model
that is like much cheaper because it doesn't need creativity.
It's like a very clear path,
like you need to run a command or you need to do some kind of something specific.
And so our thinking now is like, we probably can encode a lot of what,
what like you would do out of Claude Code to background agents that are just going
to take action on your behalf to like, nudge things along.
And then here is like finding the right balance between like, what can we trust
and like not changing core decisions of a PR,
you know, like really more into like, like nitpicks and like small fixes
without changing the meaning of a of a code change is being proposed.
This is consistent.
Sounds like the your view is there's a whole bunch of places
in which it's inarguable that the agent helped.
Like, let's apply the agents in all of those places.
Don't get into the argument of whether it's right or not, like
get it into all those places in which it can do it.
And clearly there's always like a little bit of a halo, like, you know,
you might veer a little bit into judgment, but mostly lean into the areas
in which you can inarguably say, this is correct.
So can the agent do it?
Can it not? Because that's not right.
Yeah, yeah.
And I think like super practical and kind of in high impact and
and it sounds like in review world and I guess kind of in the repo world
as a whole, you're just sort of looking for these
surrounding annoyances to sort of resolve those.
And there's so much kind of meat on that bone that you're plenty busy
sort of doing that you don't need into features quite yet.
Yeah, yeah.
Correct.
Hey everyone!
Hope you're enjoying the episode so far.
Our team is working really hard behind the scenes to bring you the best guests,
so we can have the most informative conversations about agentic development,
whether that's talking about the latest
tools, the most efficient workflows, or defining best practices.
But for whatever reason, many of you have yet to subscribe to the channel.
If you're enjoying the podcast and want us to continue to bring you
the very best content,
please do us a favor and hit that subscribe button.
It really does make a difference and lets us continue to improve
the quality of our guests and build an even better product for you.
All right, back to the episode.
I'd love to talk a little bit about
about people and around sort of hiring.
So I know you've you've had a lot of learnings about how you hire and,
and what is it that you advocate or like expect people
now when you think about promotions or kind of their career ladder.
So can you share a little bit about the learnings there
and like where you are today and maybe some key learnings?
Yeah.
Yeah. Yeah.
So so personally, I always hated LeetCode type of interviews where I think
like they were low signal, a way to like filter out some like candidates.
But I think like very often could just lead to like the wrong conclusion.
And so I've never thought that it were a nice way to hire people.
I've never liked doing them personally, and I've personally always felt like
it was kind of low signal, basically.
So, so I think AI opened the door to, to make a case to actually like review
how we do interviewing, especially coding interviews.
And so and so what we've done
is we've built a few squads to own different questions.
And with AI in the interview,
it allowed us to do much more than we could before.
And so it allowed us to basically
work on a much larger codebase in asking, like actual tasks
like somebody might be doing in their day to day and like assessing more signal
than like, yes, they could write the code in like 40 minutes
and I'm like, pass all all of the tests, but more like,
how's their how's their judgment, how's their tradeoff?
Did they understand the code?
And so like with the AI, basically the new flow for
most of the interview is going to be like, here's a code base.
It's fairly large, you need AI to understand
what it's doing, what is going on, what is this code base about.
And then afterward, like let's talk of an engineering problem.
So like maybe you want to extend this code base.
Maybe there's like a diff
like basically kind of a code review that like somebody wants to merge.
Should they.
What should we bring back in terms of like feedback detector review.
And so more like a real world scenarios.
And I think this can only happen with larger code base.
And and without AI, it would just not be possible
to go through and understand the whole context.
You know, it's like it would be more like left to luck almost.
And so and so I think it like really allowed us to step away
from LeetCode into more actual real world scenarios in the interviews.
Yeah, I love that it first of all, it's closer to the reality.
And there's actually like
a bit of a hidden question about your sort of Agent Foo,
like how how are you at kind of navigating the agent.
And so you're, you're sort of testing two things at once.
You're, you're sort of your depth in the,
in the agent usage and your ability to understand those.
And I guess it does imply, though, that this is like an in person type element.
There's no this isn't a kind of take home
code review or like coding exercise.
It has to be inside and is that you just sort of accept I guess that's a
a slight inefficiency in the sense that talk to more people that you just
take this with.
Yeah.
And how
I guess on the other side of it, like when you think about people
moving up the ladder and you think about people already in the job and doing it,
what has changed in terms of what do you assess them for,
for promotion?
So we reviewed our career guideline this year too.
And so we got together with a group to like brainstorm about like what
change in terms of expectation of like what is more kind of important today.
And so a few things to call out at the high level of like
things are like we changed
one is for is for more junior roles.
I think we saw for everybody that like we had a higher kind of expectation
about like the complexity of the work that they were going to own.
And I kind of push forward.
And so and so we updated kind of those role
to actually reflect like the new kind of baseline expectation of just like,
yeah, you can take a whole project, you want some help from somebody,
you probably kind of understand asking the right questions, learning about,
you know, the for the core competency of like being an engineer.
But compared to before,
which was usually somebody would be in a support role on a larger project.
We're finding that like most of the time now, there are they are owning
like kind of a whole work stream by themselves because they can now
and then, they just need to make sure that they're asking the right question.
And so like here we changed a bit that definition for more junior roles
in terms of more senior roles, I think what we saw is like before.
Well.
Two things.
One is in terms of like POC and experimenting,
and the second is like on on like judgment.
Should we do this?
When should we start doing something?
Is this solution the right one to the problem?
The customer is like having.
And so there's much more of like a judgment call being done.
And then in terms of.
Product and architecture tastes?
Yeah, yeah, correct, correct.
And on the POC side of things is I think before we would spend a lot of time
on like documents and RCS to talk about, like, is this the right solution
for that problems and all this and I think like there's there's like
definitely value to those questions.
But I think now we can know more certainty around
like is this going to work or not if we do a POC first.
And so you can validate assertion in practice by doing POC.
And because it's so easy
to like POC, something with AI, it's like you can do a few POC
and like compare those options before you decide into like which one
you want to actually invest in long term and like really make production ready.
And so it's like we have much more of like.
A. Of kind of a try things first
and then bring the learnings from that to make the proper decision.
And so that's a bit different from before.
Like you would need to think of everything because it was costly to create a posse.
But today. Yeah.
Try something,
run it and see what happened and then bring those learning back to
then inform the right decision you want to do.
I love that
both as a behavior and as an expectation from from people.
And I, I often say that like now that the cost of building is lower,
the relative cost of alignment is higher because it takes just as much time
to get people in a room and have a conversation.
And so investing in building more to reduce the cost of alignment,
because by the time you align, there's like something concrete and kind of more
proven is clearly like the right to trade for it.
So I love those. Yeah.
And I think it helps a lot in discussion
to just have something more concrete to talk. About.
Or like you might have concerned. This is not going to work.
But actually if you have it in a pocket and it does work, you know,
it might prove the point that I.
Okay, no, this is possible actually.
So I give you a bit more certainty in your direction.
So I think like it, it changed the whole game in terms of like discussion
of like what's the right design for a solution.
This was excellent.
And it was like just jam packed with useful advice.
I was going to ask you, what's your sort of single biggest lesson or takeaway?
But frankly, you sort of shared a whole whole pile of sort of usefulness
here and learnings for it.
So really, really appreciate you sharing it.
I'm sure the listeners are.
Instead, maybe I'll ask you like one different question, which is
what are you excited on for for what's next?
What what are you looking for forward to the most.
Yeah.
I'm, I'm really excited to basically like being able
to make better business decision and like that's kind of where we ended up on.
But like that's really my belief around AI.
Like productivity is nice and all this, you know.
But it's not like really kind of a game changer like but yeah, being able to know
and make better decision I think is really
the key thing we are.
We are a gaming with AI and this is like really what I hope we will see
happening in the business world is like, hopefully we ship better product
because we were able to try
multiple things and see what works
and what doesn't, instead of like maybe spending
kind of a whole quarter on a project that is like off ready, then you ship it
in a way because of you like invested all of that time.
You need to show something for it.
And I think that like calculus here of like
what can go out and like when you can be like, this doesn't work.
Let's start from scratch and do something different.
With the learnings we've had.
I think it's much more possible today than it's been in the past,
and I'm really excited about that.
That is super exciting.
I love the we did a roundtable at con recently and someone said that
it's not about increasing productivity, it's about increasing ambition.
And kind of I loved that sort of phrasing.
And it sounds like that's very much what you're talking about here. So
I love it.
cool.
So this has been excellent.
Thanks a lot for coming onto the show and sharing all these learnings.
And for our listeners, thanks for tuning in
and I hope you join us for the next one.
dev is brought to you by the package manager for skills and context.
Your hosts are Guy Podjarny and me, Simon Maple.
Our producer is Tom Dowler.
The AI Native Dev is not just a podcast, it's a community.
And we host monthly meetups at the Tessl offices in central London.
Visit Tessl.io forward slash community to learn more and I hope to see you there.